A Guide to the Albemarle County Land Grants and Surveys, 1769-1842
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Albemarle County Land Grants and Surveys 1769-1842
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10739,-a
This collection contains eight items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The library attained these acquisitions as bequests on December 29, 1987 and February 10, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
Collection 10739 contains Albemarle County land grants. Included are a royal grant, 1769 July, to John Moore signed by Lord Botetourt, and two Commonwealth grants to West Langford, 1798 May 1, signed by James Wood, and 1812 September 19, signed by James Barbour.
The collection 10739-a consists of an 1814 survey by William Woods of Alexander Garrett's plat in Albemarle County, Va.; an 1842 survey by Peter M. McGhee showing Thomas Boyd's plat in Albemarle County; an undated survey by McGhee and an undated plat by John White showing John Moore's Albemarle County land; and a memorandum re: an unidentified survey.
Contents List
- Collection 10739
  - To John Moore, 15 shillings, 124 acres, Albemarle County, signed by Norborne, Baron de Botetourt, Governor-General [of Virginia], Williamsburg 1769 July
  - To John Moore, 20 shillings, 175 acres, West Langford, Albemarle County, signed by James Wood, Governor of Virginia, Richmond 1798 May 1
  - To John Moore[?], 32 3/4 acres, West Langford, Albemarle County, signed by James Barbour, Governor of Virginia, Richmond 1812 Sep 19
- Collection 10739-a
  - Survey by William Woods showing Alexander Garrett's plat of 123 3/4 acres in Albemarle County 1814 April 1
  - Survey by P. M. McGhee showing Thomas Boyd's plat of 125 3/4 acres in Albemarle County 1842 Mar 31
  - Survey by Peter M. McGhee of John Moore's lands n.d.
  - Land plat by John White showing John Moore's 125 3/4 acres in Albemarle County n.d.
  - Item re lands: "Woodrow's courses from the forked chestnut on path to Mrs. Gibson's line... ." n.d.